A Guide to the Frank Dempster Sherman Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8527-a
Frank Dempster Sherman Collection 1882-1909
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8527
11 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1963 Dec 17 1967 Feb 20
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem, " For my Father ", 1882 Oct 23; AMsS, 1 p.
    [On verso of a 1 p. ALS, 1882 Oct 23, Frank Dempster Sherman to his father; expresses love to his father in a birthday greeting.]
  - Poem, beginning "March, and the larch is bending.. .", 1888 Mar 16; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, " The Poet's Joy ", 1901 Oct 30; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Includes ANS to "Dear Harry"; asks for $15 for the poem; hopes Harry will keep it.]
  - Poem, " Psyche ", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, " The First Snowfall ", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to Richard Watson Gilder, 1891 Jan 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Expresses gratitude for Gilder's interest in the work of Charles Henry Luders, who recently died; speaks of his exquisite poems, "
    The Dead Nymph
    , " printed in Scribner's in 1888, and "
    The Four Winds
    "; submits a sonnet of his own, along with some of his friend's poems.]
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to [William] Bliss Carman, 1891 Feb 13; ALS, 2 p.
    [Requests copies of the
    Independent
    in which poems by [Thomas Bailey] Aldrich were published, starting 1884; thanks him for sending a copy of lyric which he has put in the Carman envelope.]
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to Howes Norris Jr., 1896 Sep 12; ALS, 1 p.
    [Includes autographed card on verso, 1884 March 29, with a verse beginning "wishing you all success in your.. ."; regards his and Norris' postage stamp collections.]
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to Editor, Genealogical Department, The Transcript, 1904 Aug 31; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests a copy of
    The Transcript
    in which an article about his grandfather James Sherman appeared; says a clipping of the article was sent to him by the late F. C. Pierce of Chicago. ]
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to David Pell Secor, 1907 Apr 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for the lock of hair, from the author of "
    America
    , " and for the charming sketch; recalls their visit a few days ago and the visit by Clinton Scollard. ]
  - Frank Dempster Sherman to Mary Brownson Church, 1909 Apr 14; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs her that William Watson's sonnet "
    To Thomas Bailey Aldrich
    " is included in Watson's volume "
    The Hope of the World
    , " John Lane, 1898; guesses that it appeared in print for the first time in
    The Academy
    says the Watson sonnet is also included in Aldrich's
    Songs and Sonnets
    . ]